I hope the happiness you will have
我祈愿将造访两人的幸福
is so much more than what I received.
是我所得到的 好几倍
Yuito, Kasane.
结人 重
I love you.
我爱你们
Mother...
妈妈…
This is strange.
好奇怪
Wakana went back,
若菜小姐回去了
but the Kunad Gate is still here.
但是 岐之门并没有消失
But how?
怎么会这样
Yuito...
结人
Yuito, are you all right?
结人 你没事吧
Let him get some rest.
先回去让他好好休息吧
Yuito...
结人…
-Yuito... -You're awake.
-结人 -你醒啦
SCARLET NEXUS
《绯红结系》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立关系的方法吗
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
有个麻烦的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在寻求某人的拥抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虚无之间
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以输赢之间为目标
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
注意别让信任走向尽头 务必小心
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你脑中那冷感的轨道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
摇滚的日子未曾有过的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光荣早已埋葬在某处
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
这一瞬间寂寞孤独的野兽
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世间道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地联系着
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那脑中冷感的正义
THE TWO BROTHERS
(兄与弟)
There is no one here.
这里没人
The search team is on the move again.
搜索队的人 好像继续移动了
That was too close.
好险
But what took them so long to find this place?
不过为何之前都没被搜查过呢
When I hacked into the system,
之前黑客进去时
I made some changes to the data.
我顺便在资料里动了点手脚
I marked the place as "searched."
打上"已搜查过"的记号
I bet they are searching from scratch because they couldn't find us.
他们一直找不到我们的所在位置 所以才从头开始搜寻吧
Yuito, are you feeling better now?
结人 你没事了吗
Yeah. Don't worry about me.
是啊 不用担心
Did you undo all the entanglements?
你们 真的解开所有的纠缠了吗
We detected entanglements
我们感觉到的纠缠
from 11 years ago and 50 years into the future,
有11年前的及50年后的
and from the time when Yakumo was alive.
还有 八云皇存在的年代
We untied those entanglements.
这些全部都解开了
How is Yakumo Sumeragi's timeline connected to the Kunad Gate?
跟八云皇存在的时代有什么关系
We saw how he got assassinated.
因为我们看到八云皇被暗杀的场面
That caused a dimensional entanglement.
所以产生了维度纠缠
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
Yakumo was never assassinated.
八云才没被暗杀呢
Yeah, we've never heard of such a thing.
是啊 从没听说过
It wasn't in the history lesson either.
历史也没学过
We're not sure either.
我们也不清楚
But we did saw it.
但确实看到了
Yakumo Sumeragi was assassinated by Karen.
八云皇 被卡连杀死的场面
What?
什么
Karen used the Arahabaki to time travel.
卡连利用荒吐神 做了时间跳跃
But are you saying he traveled back in time to when Yakumo was still alive?
你是说 他回到八云的时代了吗
Are you sure the people you saw were Yakumo and Karen?
你们看到的真的是八云和卡连吗
There was no doubt about it.
没看错
He wore a mask just as the legend says.
跟传闻一样 戴着面具
A mask...
面具…
A mask!
面具
That's it! It's the mask!
对喔 是面具
That explains everything.
那就能说明一切了
Kagero, tell us what you know.
阳炎 别自己一个人理解
Explain it to us.
快点说明
Do you know why Yakumo was wearing a mask?
大家应该知道为何八云戴着面具吧
He was injured in an accident.
因事故而受了重伤
Indeed.
没错
Ever since he put on that mask,
自从他戴上那副面具
he never showed up in public again.
就不再出现在众人面前了
There were rumors about him acting like a completely different person.
有传闻说他简直是变了个人
His personality changed? Could it be...
变了个人… 难道
The real Yakumo Sumeragi was murdered by Karen who traveled back in time.
真正的八云 被来自未来的卡连杀害
He replaced him under the disguise of that mask.
然后戴上面具替换
So Yakumo was Karen...
八云是卡连
Does that mean Karen is also Yuito's ancestor?
那 卡连是结人的祖先啰
That is impossible.
不 不可能
He already had children before the injury.
他在受伤前 就已经有孩子了
But why would Karen do this?
不过 为何卡连要这么做
The reason doesn't really matter.
原因不重要吧
What matters now is finding a way to destroy the Kunad Gate.
快点想办法解决岐之门才是重点
If our assumption is correct,
如果刚才说的是事实
there should be a dimensional entanglement that formed when Karen time traveled.
应该有卡连跳越时空到八云时代时 留下的维度纠缠
I agree.
应该有吧
We just need to undo that as well.
只要解开就行了吧
But we found no such thing.
可是 我们并没看到…
What now?
那该怎么办
The entanglement created by Wakana
因若菜产生的纠缠
can only be undone by herself.
只有她能解除
I see.
原来如此
The entanglement my brother created can only be undone by him.
因哥哥产生的纠缠 也只有哥哥能解开
Yes, that's how it works.
没错 应该就是这样
We must get Karen to Chronos Terminal and make him undo the entanglement.
只能带卡连进克洛诺斯航站 让他解开维度纠缠了
I doubt he would come quietly.
他会这么听话吗
Wataru, can you pinpoint Karen's location?
渡 能确认卡连的所在位置吗
No. I can't track him at all.
不行 根本抓不到他的动向
I might have an idea about where he is.
我可能…知道他在哪
Do you remember?
大家还记得吗
Yakumo Sumeragi is still alive.
八云皇还活着
He's still alive?
还活着
He is in his slumber right beneath the Suoh Capital.
他正在苏芳的地下深处沉眠
He is bidding his time for revenge.
现在仍在等待 复仇的瞬间
Beneath the Suoh Capital...
苏芳的地下深处…
The first place that comes to our mind
说到八云会在的地方
is the Sumeragi crypt.
第一个想到的是皇陵
But that is a tourism destination.
可是 那里是观光地耶
What do you think, Yuito?
结人你觉得呢
That's your family's crypt.
那是你家的陵墓吧
I've never been to that place.
但我没进去过
But my brother might have visited it.
不过 我想哥哥可能…
Does Chief Sumeragi know Karen could very likely be Yakumo?
本部长是否知道 八云可能是卡连这件事
I have no idea. We've never met again since that day.
不知道 那之后我就没见过他了
The Chief has been stripped of his authority.
本部长被剥夺了权限
He's been grounded.
现在被禁止外出
He's been held accountable for leaking
他因泄漏情报让全国国民知道
top-secret information to the public.
所以被追究了责任
He became our scapegoat.
这就是背黑锅吧
NO CONNECTION
(无法通信)
I can't reach him.
打不通
Suoh is in chaos.
苏芳正呈现混乱状态
Now is our chance to strike.
我认为这是进攻的好机会
But the Kunad Gate still poses a great threat to us all.
可是 岐之门的问题也很棘手
We'll deal with it after we're done with Suoh.
解决苏芳后再来想办法
Now is not the time for petty arguments.
现在不是起争执的时候
Yuito...
结人
Don't cry.
别哭
You must learn how to treat your own wounds.
至少学会怎么自己处理伤口吧
As a Sumeragi, you shouldn't wait for help.
身为皇家人 不是接受谁的帮助
Stand firmly on your own legs
而是必须靠自己的双脚 站稳在这世界上
for your country New Himuka.
这也是为了国家 为了新日向
Be strong, Yuito!
变坚强吧 结人
Fubuki...
吹雪
I got a message from my brother.
哥哥传来的讯息
He wants me to go there alone.
他要我自己过去
It's too risky.
太危险了
That's probably a trap.
搞不好是陷阱
If I remember correctly, the Chief wanted Yuito's brain.
我记得本部长想得到结人的脑
The power you possess
你所拥有的力量
is the ability to control gravity.
是特别的"操纵重力"的脑力
We need that power.
我们需要这种脑力
When you use your power to shake the Extinction Belt
你们使用超脑力 撼动断绝之带
and pave the path to Moon,
展开至月球道路之时
that's when our revenge is complete.
就是完成复仇的时刻
To shake the Extinction Belt?
撼动断绝之带
We don't have that kind of power.
我们没有这股力量
It's possible with every brain in our country via SAS
以SAS全国民的脑 就有可能成功
You're insane!
开什么玩笑
Even users like us can't handle the load from SAS!
就算是超脑力者 也难以承受SAS
It doesn't matter.
无法承受也无所谓
All we need is their brains and body parts.
我们需要的 只有脑和身体零件
Well?
怎么办
I'll go alone.
我一个人去
I will track Yuito's location.
我会准确地掌握结人的所在位置
Thanks.
谢谢
Don't let your guard down.
别大意
Contact us as soon as anything comes up.
发生什么事立刻联络我们
Yes.
我知道
The reaction is getting stronger.
反应越来越强
The Kunad Gate has become even more violent.
岐之门的反应 越来越活跃了
It doesn't seem like a trap.
看样子不是陷阱
I don't have the authority to dispatch the OSF troops.
我现在没有调动怪伐军的能力
I was told you had been grounded.
听说你被禁止外出
But I wasn't being monitored.
但并没有被监视
Don't underestimate me.
你可别小看我了
I'll kill you
杀了你
and take your brain.
夺取你的脑部
Why?
为什么
Why didn't the time travel work?
为什么…时间跳跃失败了
There is no Other in this area.
这附近是怪异出没地区
Let's settle this quickly.
尽快解决吧
I'm sure Major General Fubuki told you our plan.
你应该听吹雪连队长说过了吧
Yes. He told me you were trying to gain access to the Sumeragi crypt.
听过了 他说你想进入皇陵
Time travel...
时间跳跃
He even told me Karen was Yakumo.
卡连其实是八云皇
This is beyond absurd.
愚蠢至极
These claims are nothing more than baseless speculations.
这些都是毫无根据的推测吧
But I want to give it a shot.
但我仍想赌一把
in order to undo the Kunad Gate.
这也是为了消除岐之门
That is why I need your help.
所以 希望你协助我
Don't be so naive.
少天真了
I have lost all authority as the Chief,
我虽已失去怪伐军本部长的权限
but I am still the head of the Sumeragi family.
但我是皇家当主
My intention to fulfill Yakumo's dying wish hasn't changed.
需实现八云皇夙愿的这件事仍不变
Now that I think about it,
仔细想想
pointing a gun at a power user is probably pointless.
拿这东西指着超脑力者没什么用
But I doubt you would hurt your own brother.
但你应该不会伤害你的亲生兄长吧
However, I am not you.
不过我不同
For the sake of my mission,
为了达成使命
not even my own brother...
即便是自己的弟弟…
Others have shown up in the area!
结人周遭出现了怪异
They are coming.
有人来了
Are these the OSF troops from Suoh?
是苏芳的怪伐军吗
To think they'd actually find this place...
竟然找到这里
Brother, back down!
哥哥 快退后
Damn it, there are too many of them.
可恶 数量太多了
Yuito!
结人
Brother, are you hurt?
哥哥 没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
You could have just left me behind.
为何不丢下我
You should have just run away.
你一个人应该逃得了才对
Maybe I should.
或许吧
But you wouldn't find the crypt if I died.
我死了 就进不去皇陵了吗
But Brother and I...
可是 我跟哥哥…
Don't worry.
没问题的
You are both our children.
你们都是爸爸妈妈的孩子啊
It's true Karen traveled back in time and disguised as Yakumo.
卡连和八云 还有时间跳跃的事 都是真的
I met Mom from the past.
我见过过去的妈妈了
I'm telling you the truth.
我真的没骗人
I hope you understand.
只是希望 哥哥能理解
You seem to have a better grasp of the situation of this world.
你似乎 越来越了解这个世界了
You should know by now
那你应该知道
how twisted New Himuka actually is.
新日向这个国家有多么扭曲
That twist was created by none other than the Moon.
而创造出扭曲的 正是月球
They created the Extinction Belt and send the Others our way.
他们创造了断绝之带 把怪异送了过来
People of Earth suffer because of them.
害地球的人们持续受苦
Destroying the Moon is the duty of our family.
灭了月球 正是我们皇家的使命
We have made great sacrifices for this cause,
为此我们的确牺牲了很多人
we've deceived the people.
也欺骗了国民
However, it was all for the sake of our revenge
但…这都是为了 报复这两千年来的仇恨
and to realize Yakumo's ambition.
并实现八云的夙愿
This isn't what he wanted.
这并不是八云所期望的
Everything will be pointless if everyone dies for the sake of extinction.
为了毁灭人类而牺牲大家 这不就没任何意义吗
Brother, you are just like the people in Togetsu.
哥哥你和渡月一样
You are being shackled by the ancestor you've never even met.
只是被从没见过的古人束缚了
This country is indeed twisted.
这个国家确实扭曲了
The OSF I respected was hiding all kinds of dirty secrets.
我憧憬的怪伐军 藏有污秽的秘密
Even so, I still want to fight as one of them.
即便如此 我仍想以怪伐军的身分战斗
I still want to protect the people.
我想保护他人的心 没有任何改变
Don't follow the words of someone from over 200 years ago.
不是遵从2000年前某人的话语
Create your own future.
而是凭着自己的意志创造未来
That's how my friends and I made it this far.
我跟我同伴 都是这样走过来的
We'll keep moving forward.
以后也会继续走下去
Be strong, Yuito.
变坚强吧 结人
You somehow managed to stop Togetsu's plan.
你似乎阻止了渡月的企图
I guess you've avenged our mother.
也算是为母亲报了仇
You've done many things I wished I could've done.
你帮我做了我想做的事
You'll have my thanks for that.
我就…先谢谢你吧
Brother...
哥哥…
Yuito.
结人
This is the key to Sumeragi crypt.
这是进入皇陵的钥匙
I don't agree with what you do.
我并不认为你们是正确的
But you've come this far to prove your point.
但你都说到这个地步了 就证明给我看吧
So prove to me that you're right.
证明你们的做法是对的
Brother...
哥哥
Yuito, you must live on.
结人 你要活下去
No!
别去
Brother!
哥哥
Prove to me your way is the right one!
证明给我看 你的想法是正确的
Back off!
闪开
Brother!
哥哥
Yuito, watch out!
结人 别大意
I told you not to let your guard down.
跟你说过别大意了
Kasane and everyone...
重 各位
Are you hurt, Chief Sumeragi?
有没有受伤 本部长
Fubuki? Why are you here?
吹雪 这到底是怎么回事
Suoh and Seiran signed a temporary truce.
苏芳和青蓝签订了 暂时性的停战协议
A truce...
停战协议
To stop the destruction brought by Kunad Gate,
为了解决岐之门逐渐失控的问题
Major General Fubuki managed to persuade both sides.
吹雪连队长居中交涉的
Yuito's status as a wanted fugitive has been rescinded.
结人被取消反叛者的身分了
Wataru is back at the headquarters too.
渡也回到总部了
They have delayed our punishment,
我们的处分也予以保留
but only for the moment.
虽然只是暂时的
I see.
这样啊
But we can't relax just yet.
不过 还不能放心
Yeah. The truce means the situation has gone even worse.
没错 这就表示事态严重了
Watch out!
各位 小心点
I'm so scared!
好可怕喔…
Others detected above Suoh!
苏方上空出现了怪异
They are large in number.
数量惊人
The earthquake just now
受到刚才地震的影响
knocked out the defense system.
防卫系统出现故障
Our anti-Other artillery system lost 30 percent of its capacity!
对怪异高射炮 可出动机率下降30%
We should head back to Suoh.
赶快回苏方吧
Yes. Let's go.
好 动作快…
Yuito...
结人
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭开被阻挡的摇曳阳炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
从未见过
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐惧翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
华丽舞步的鸟儿
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染红的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追过了强风
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千变万化的世界里
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交错的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持续寻找明天的行径方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前进
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏惧何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
INTO THE CRYPT
(前进皇陵)